Guide to the Graduate School Records, 1924-2014 UA.24.01.0001
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Graduate School records
1924-2014
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Duke University. Graduate School
UA.24.01.0001
71 Linear Feet 60,000 items
The Graduate School of Arts and Sciences at Duke University was formally established in 1926, although some graduate instruction had been offered previously at Trinity College and Duke University. In 1968 the name was shortened to the Graduate School. Collection includes student records, admission applications, correspondence, dissertation abstracts, brochures, memoranda, newsletters, minutes, financial records, grant records, statistics, and other material generated by the Graduate School. Prominent individuals featured within the collection include Willam Glasson, Paul Gross, John McKinney, and Richard Predmore.
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
For a period of twenty-five years from the origin of the material, permission in writing from the office of origin and the University Archivist is required for use. After twenty-five years, records that have been processed may be consulted with the permission of the University Archivist.
In accordance with the Family Education Rights and Privacy Act of 1974 as amended, Duke University permits students to inspect their education records and limits the disclosure of personally identifiable information from education records.
Records, such as search committee files or others pertaining to employment where individuals are identified, are closed for 70 years.
Electronic records in this collection have been migrated to a library server and digital use copies can only be accessed onsite in the Rubenstein Library Reading Room. To request access, please contact Research Services before coming to use these records.
Unprocessed materials are closed pending processing.
In off-site storage; 48 hours advance notice is required for use.
Provenance
The Graduate School Records were received by the University Archives as transfers between 1962-2014.
Historical Note
The Graduate School of Arts and Sciences at Duke University was formally established in 1926, although some graduate instruction had been offered previously at Trinity College and Duke University. In 1968 the name was shortened to the Graduate School. Deans of the Graduate School have included William H. Glasson (1926-1938), Paul M. Gross (1947-1952), Richard L. Predmore (1962-1969), and John C. McKinney (1969-1981).
Collection Overview
Collection includes student records, admission applications, correspondence, dissertation abstracts, brochures, memoranda, newsletters, minutes, financial records, grant records, statistics, and other material generated by the Graduate School. It also includes correspondence, subject files, and other records of the Dean of the Graduate School. Subjects include admissions, foreign students, international studies, minority enrollment, grants-in-aid, graduate courses, and graduate faculty.
Arrangement note
The first series of Graduate School files is comprised of a number of separate accessions that were combined by University Archives Staff. Each of the following series is a subsequent accession. Accessions are arranged in chronological order. Within each series, files have been maintained in the original order in which they were received.
Related Material
Paul M. Gross Papers, 1935-1979
Duke University Archives
William Henry Glasson Papers, 1891-1946
Duke University Archives
Round Table on Science and Public Affairs Records, 1973-1983
Duke University Archives
Gross, Paul Magnus, 1895-1986; McKinney, John C., 1920-; Predmore, Richard Lionel; Duke University. Graduate School of Arts and Sciences; Duke University. Graduate School; Glasson, William Henry, 1874-1946; Duke University -- Administration; Duke University -- Dissertations; Duke University -- Faculty
- Subject Files, 1924-1994 and undated
  Scope and Contents note
  This series of Graduate School files is comprised of a number of separate accessions that were combined by University Archives Staff. Accession numbers include: UA62-494, UA63-91, UA64-168, UA66-210, UA70-59, UA73-76, UA74-37, UA74-82, UA75-87, UA75-93, UA2000-3, UA2000-82.
  - Academic Salaries and Living Costs, 1955-1956 (Box 1)
  - Academic Standards Committee, 1956-1957 (Box 1)
  - Address to Principals, Supervisors, MEH, 1955 Feb. (Box 1)
  - Ph.D. Current Address Survey, 1951 (Box 1)
  - Administrative Policies and Regulations, 1937-1943 (Box 1)
  - Special Administrative Studies, 1938-1942 (Box 1)
  - Admissions, Correspondence, 1954-1978 (Box 1)
  - Advisory Committee on Graduate Studies of I.I.E. New York, 1953 Oct. 29 (Box 1)
  - Aesthetics, Art, and Music (Box 1)
  - African Student Applications (Box 1)
  - Alumni Office (Box 1)
  - Alumni Affairs, 1954-1955 (Box 1)
  - American Association of Universities (Box 1)
  - American Council on Education (Box 1)
  - American Council on Education, 1966 (Box 1)
  - Anatomy (Box 1)
  - Ancient Languages and Literatures (Box 1)
  - Foundation Support, Applications for (Box 1)
  - Association of Graduate Schools in Association of American Universities-New York, 1953 Oct. 26-1953 Oct. 28 (Box 2)
  - Association of Graduate Schools in Association of American Universities-Northwestern University, Evanston, Ill., 1954 Oct. 25-1954 Oct. 27 (Box 2)
  - Association of Graduate Schools, 1955 Oct. 30-1955 Nov. 1 (Box 2)
  - Association of Graduate Schools-Chicago, Ill., Conference, 1956 Oct. 24-1956 Oct. 25 (Box 2)
  - Association of Graduate Schools Correspondence (Box 2)
  - Association of Graduate Schools Correspondence-Committee on Policies in Graduate Education (Box 2)
  - Association of Graduate Schools Drafts, etc., of Material Pertinent to Report of Committee on Policy In Graduate Education (Box 2)
  - Association of Graduate Schools Executive Committee (Box 2)
  - Association of Graduate Schools International Student Exchange (Box 2)
  - Association of Graduate Schools Membership (Box 3)
  - Association of Graduate Schools Miscellaneous (Box 3)
  - Association of Graduate Schools Program of Meeting, 1956 Oct. 24-1956 Oct. 25 (Box 3)
  - Association of Graduate Schools Questionnaires (Box 3)
  - Policies in Graduate Education, Committee on, Questionnaire Responses (Box 3)
  - Association of Graduate Schools Report - Committee on Policies in Graduate Education (Box 3)
  - Association of Graduate Schools Reports (Box 3)
  - Assisting Duties, Hours, etc., Departmental, 1954 (Box 3)
  - Admission Policies (Box 3)
  - Assisting Duties, 1955-1956 (Box 3)
  - Assisting Duties, 1956-1957 (Box 3)
  - Assisting Duties, 1957-1958 (Box 3)
  - Association of American Colleges (Box 3)
  - Association of American Universities, 1939-1941 (Box 4)
  - Association of American Universities, 1941-1946 (Box 4)
  - Association of American Universities, 1946-1948 (Box 4)
  - Association of American Universities, Chicago, 1952 Oct. 26 -1952 Oct. 28 (Box 4)
  - Association of American Universities (A.A.U.) Admission of Graduate Students, 1940 (Box 4)
  - Association of Research Libraries (Box 4)
  - Atlanta Committee on Standards and Reports, 1953 Nov. 5-1953 Nov. 7 (Box 4)
  - Awards (Box 4)
  - Awards, New Plan Beginning, 1955 (Box 4)
  - Awards, 1955-1956 (Box 4)
  - Awards, 1956-1957 (Box 4)
  - Awards, 1957-1958 (Box 4)
  - Awards, 1952-1953 (Box 5)
  - Awards, Form Letters, 1953 Apr. 1 (Box 5)
  - Awards, Budget, 1953-1954 (Box 5)
  - Awards, From Other Universities, 1955 (Box 5)
  - Awards, From Other Universities, 1955-1956 (Box 5)
  - Awards, 1963-1964 (Box 5)
  - Awards, 1958-1959 (Box 5)
  - Awards, From Other Institutions, 1958-1959 (Box 5)
  - Awards and Recommendations, List of, 1937-1943 (Box 5)
  - Awards, List of, 1940-1942 (Box 6)
  - Awards, Departmental Recommendations for Fellowships, Scholarships, and Assistantships, 1944-1945 (Box 6)
  - Awards and Recommendations, List of, 1944-1946 (Box 6)
  - Awards Lists, 1946-1974 (Box 6)
  - Awards, Graduate School, 1947-1948 (Box 6)
  - Awards, Graduate, 1948-1949 (Box 6)
  - Awards, 1949-1950 (Box 6)
  - Awards, 1950-1951 (Box 6)
  - Awards, 1951-1952 (Box 6)
  - Awards, Budget, 1954-1955 (Box 7)
  - Awards, Announcements (Box 7)
  - Awards, Correspondence (Box 7)
  - Awards, Departmental Recommendations, 1950-1951 (Box 7)
  - Awards, Departmental Recommendations, 1951-1952 (Box 7)
  - Awards, Fellowship Applications, 1946-1947 (Box 7)
  - Berelson, Bernard (Box 7)
  - Biochemistry, Department of, 1946-1947 (Box 7)
  - Biochemistry, Scheduling Problem (Box 7)
  - Biographical Data and List of Publications for Professors no Longer Teaching at Duke University (Box 7)
  - British Commonwealth (Box 7)
  - Botany Department, 1946-1949 (Box 7)
  - Botany Department (Box 7)
  - Botany Department, 1957-1965 (Box 8)
  - Botany Department, 1960-1963 (Box 8)
  - Botany Department, 1966-1969 (Box 8)
  - Bowman, Dr., Correspondence, Admissions, 1957-1958 (Box 8)
  - Bowman, Dr., Correspondence, English (Box 8)
  - Bowman, Dr., Correspondence, Personal, 1957-1958 (Box 8)
  - Bowman, Dr., Correspondence, Foreign Students, 1957-1958 (Box 8)
  - Bowman, Dr., Correspondence, Miscellaneous, 1957-1958 (Box 8)
  - Budget (Box 9)
  - Budget (Box 9)
  - Budget (Prior Years) (Box 9)
  - Bulletins and Fellowship Announcements, Requests for Addressograph Plates Made (Box 9)
  - Bulletin, 1963-1964 (Box 9)
  - Bulletin, 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - Bulletin, 1965-1966 (Box 9)
  - Bulletin, 1966-1967 (Box 9)
  - Public Information, Bureau of (Box 9)
  - Testing and Guidance, Bureau of (Box 9)
  - Campus Security (Box 9)
  - Campus Security Committee (Box 9)
  - Car Registration (Box 9)
  - Carbide and Carbon (Box 10)
  - Carnegie Material, 1956-1957 (Box 10)
  - Cartter, Dr., Personal Correspondence, 1959 (Box 10)
  - Cartter, Dr., Personal Correspondence, 1960 (Box 10)
  - Cartter, Dr., Personal, 1961-1962 (Box 10)
  - Study of Higher Education, Center for the, The University of Michigan (Box 10)
  - Central Records Office (Box 10)
  - Chemistry Department (Box 10)
  - Chemistry Department, 1956-1958 (Box 10)
  - Chemistry Department, Three Year Reviews, 1962 (Box 10)
  - Chemistry Department, 1958-1963 (Box 11)
  - Class Census Report Summary, Spring Semester, 1959-1960 (Box 11)
  - Clyde, Paul H. (Box 11)
  - Codes (for Expenses) (Box 11)
  - Cokesbury, 1963-1964 (Box 11)
  - College Teachers Training (Box 11)
  - Colleges and Universities attended by applicants, conferring undergraduate degrees (Box 11)
  - Commencement Material, General, 1945-1948 (Box 11)
  - Commencement, 1947 Sept. 1948 June (Box 11)
  - Commencement, 1949 June (Box 11)
  - Commencement, 1950 June (Box 11)
  - Commencement, 1951 June (Box 11)
  - Commencement, 1952 June (Box 11)
  - Commencements, Sept., 1948-1952 (Box 11)
  - Commencement (CSS), 1952 Sept., 1953 June (Box 11)
  - Commencement, 1953 June, 1953 Sept. (Box 11)
  - Commencement, 1954 June, 1953 Sept. (Box 11)
  - Commencement, 1955 June, 1954 Sept. (Box 11)
  - Commencement, 1955 Sept. (Box 12)
  - Commencement, 1956 Sept. 1 (Box 12)
  - Commencement: Degree Candidates, Intentions, 1955-1956 (Box 12)
  - Commencement: Dean Hobbs Presentation of Candidates to Have Degrees Conferred, 1955-1956 (Box 12)
  - Commencement: Programs of Graduation Exercises, etc. (Box 12)
  - Commencement: General Correspondence, 1955-1956 (Box 12)
  - Commencement: Degrees Awarded, 1955-1956 (Box 12)
  - Commencement: Degrees Awarded, 1956-1957 (Box 12)
  - Commencement: Degrees Awarded, 1957-1958 (Box 12)
  - Commencement Programs, Set of, 1928-1948 (Box 12)
  - Commencement Programs (Box 12)
  - Commission on English - Summer Institute (Box 12)
  - Buildings and Grounds, Committee on (Box 12)
  - Course of Instruction, Committee on (Box 12)
  - Schedule Revision for History, Economics, Political Science, Committee on (Box 12)
  - Select Dean of College of Engineering, Committee to (Box 12)
  - Survey of Departments' Competence to Offer Doctoral Program, Committee on, 1946 (Box 12)
  - Commonwealth: Correspondence (Box 13)
  - Commonwealth Fund, The (Box 13)
  - Commonwealth Studies Center, 1958-1959 (Box 13)
  - Deans of Southern Graduate Schools, Conference of - R. McCutcheon, 1932-1944 (Box 13)
  - Deans of Southern Graduate Schools, Conference of, 1945 (Box 13)
  - Deans of Southern Graduate Schools, Conference of, 1935-1947 (Box 13)
  - Deans of Southern Graduate Schools, Conference of, 1949-1951 (Box 14)
  - Deans of Southern Graduate Schools, Conference of, 1954 Nov. 21-1954 Nov. 22 (Box 14)
  - Deans of Southern Graduate Schools, Conference of, New Orleans, 1955 Nov. 20-1955 Nov. 21 (Box 14)
  - Deans of Southern Graduate Schools, Conference of, 1956-1957 (Box 14)
  - Southern Deans Committee, Conference of - Institutional Membership, 1957-1958 (Box 14)
  - Deans of Southern Graduate Schools, Conference of, 1961 (Box 14)
  - Correspondence: General, 1954, 1956-1957, 1957-1958 (Box 14)
  - Correspondence: Graduate Faculty, 1956-1957 (Box 14)
  - Correspondence, Miscellaneous (Box 14)
  - Evaluation of Foreign Student Credentials, Council on (Box 15)
  - Graduate Schools in the U.S., Council of (Box 15)
  - Southern Universities, Inc., Council of (Box 15)
  - Credit toward Degree (Box 15)
  - Danforth Foundation, 1958-1962 (Box 15)
  - Deans of Graduate Schools, Acting, 1948 Summer (Box 15)
  - Deans of Graduate Schools, Southern, New Orleans, 1952 Nov. 23-1952 Nov. 24 (Box 15)
  - Deans of Graduate Schools, Southern, 1953 Nov. 5-1953 Nov. 7 (Box 15)
  - Deans of Graduate Schools, Southern (Box 15)
  - Delinquent lists received from Treasurer's Office, etc. (keep for reference), 1952 May 3 (Box 15)
  - Department of State (International Educational Exchange Service) (Box 15)
  - Development of Scientists and Engineers, Committee on (Box 15)
  - Graduate Studies Form Letters, Director of (Box 15)
  - Graduate Studies, Directors of, Items for Agenda (Box 15)
  - Deans of Graduate Schools in course of academic year, Copies of letters and memoranda sent to (Box 15)
  - Graduate Studies, Directors of, 1948-1949 (Box 15)
  - Graduate Studies, Directors of, Meeting, 1954 Oct. (Box 15)
  - Graduate Studies, Directors of, Meeting, 1954 Feb. 12 (Box 15)
  - Graduate Studies, Director of, Summer and Winter (Box 15)
  - Distinguished Teaching Fellows, 1962-1963 (Box 15)
  - Distinguished Teaching Fellows, 1963-1964 (Box 15)
  - Disturbed Children Program (Box 16)
  - Education Degree, Doctor of, General File, 1940-1949 (Box 16)
  - James B. Duke Fellowships, to, 1959 (Box 16)
  - Doctoral Dissertation (Box 16)
  - East Carolina Teachers College, Correspondence (Box 16)
  - Economic Census and Business Administration, 1960 Fall (Box 16)
  - Economics Department, 1938-1948 (Box 16)
  - Economics Department (Box 16)
  - Economics Department, 1955-1958 (Box 16)
  - Edens, President A. H. (Box 16)
  - Edens, President A. H., 1956-1957, 1957-1958 (Box 16)
  - Education Department, 1941-1949 (Box 16)
  - Education Department (Box 16)
  - Education Department, Miscellaneous Documents (Box 17)
  - Education Department, Visiting Professors, circa 1950-1959 (Box 17)
  - Educational Testing Service, 1962-1966 (Box 17)
  - Educational Testing Service Foreign Language Tests (Box 17)
  - Education Department, 1956-1958 (Box 17)
  - Edwards, Professor Charles W., 1933-1937 (Box 17)
  - Elwood, Dr. Charles A., 1930 (Box 17)
  - Employment Applications (Box 17)
  - Engineering College (Box 17)
  - Engineering College (Box 17)
  - Engineering College, Nuclear (Box 17)
  - English Department, 1946-1949 (Box 17)
  - English Department (Box 17)
  - English Census, 1960 Fall (Box 18)
  - English 100, English for Foreign Students (Box 18)
  - Enrollment (Box 18)
  - Candidates for Degrees, Estimated, 1950 (Box 18)
  - Educational Testing Service Scores, German, 1964 July 15 (Box 18)
  - Examination Procedure for Ph.D. (Box 18)
  - Examination Procedure, Doctoral and Masters, 1935 (Box 18)
  - Examination Schedule (Box 18)
  - Executive Committee, Graduate School Council, new business and unfinished business, 1939-1940 (Box 18)
  - Executive Committee, 1944-1948 (Box 18)
  - Executive Committee, Discussions, 1955 Oct. (Box 18)
  - Executive Committee, Committee Reports, 1956-1957 (Box 18)
  - Executive Committee, 1956-1958 (Box 18)
  - Executive Committee, Agendas, 1957-1958 (Box 18)
  - Executive Committee, Agendas, 1958-1959 (Box 18)
  - Executive Committee, 1962-1963 (Box 18)
  - Executive Committee, Agendas, 1963-1964 (Box 18)
  - Executive Committee, 1963-1964 (Box 18)
  - Executive Committee, 1964-1965 (Box 18)
  - Executive Committee, 1965 (Box 18)
  - Executive Committee Minutes, 1965-1966 (Box 19)
  - Executive Committee, 1966-1967 (Box 19)
  - Executive Committee, Agendas (Box 19)
  - Executive Committee, Agendas, 1956-1957 (Box 19)
  - Executive Committee, 1959-1960 (Box 19)
  - Executive Committee, Agendas, 1960-1961 (Box 19)
  - Executive Committee, Correspondence (Box 19)
  - Executive Committee, Correspondence, 1955-1956 (Box 19)
  - Executive Committee, Members (Box 19)
  - Faculty Approved for 300-Level Courses, 1955 Oct. 26 (Box 19)
  - Faculty, Courses Approved for (Box 19)
  - Faculty Club Committee (Box 19)
  - Faculty Club, 1956-1957 (Box 19)
  - Fees (Box 19)
  - Fellowship Program for College Teachers, Pending (Box 19)
  - Fellowship, Scholarships, and Assistantship Announcements, 1931-1955 (Box 19)
  - Fellowship, Scholarship List (Association of American Universities) (Box 19)
  - Fellowships, Name - Fellowships, National, 1960-1961 (Box 19)
  - Few, President (Box 20)
  - Ford Foundation (Box 20)
  - Ford Foundation (Box 20)
  - Ford Foundation, Correspondence (Box 20)
  - Ford Foundation, Correspondence (Box 20)
  - Ford Grant (Box 20)
  - Foreign Language Tests for Graduate Students, Educational Testing Service (Box 20)
  - Foreign Students (Box 20)
  - Foreign Students, Advisor (Box 20)
  - Foreign Students, Aid (Box 20)
  - Foreign Students, Application to extend time of stay (Box 20)
  - Foreign Students, Awards (Box 20)
  - Foreign Students, Forms for Employment (Box 20)
  - Foreign Students, Correspondence (Box 20)
  - Foreign Students, Immigration and Naturalization (Box 20)
  - Foreign Students, Information (Box 21)
  - Foreign Students, Pakistan (Box 21)
  - Foreign Students List, Graduate, 1953-1954 (Box 21)
  - Foreign Students, 1945 Sept. (Box 21)
  - Foreign Students List, 1962 Fall (Box 21)
  - Foreign Student List, 1963-1964 (Box 21)
  - Foreign Students, Orientation Program Report (Box 21)
  - Foreign Students, Responses to letters concerning roommates (Box 21)
  - Foreign Students, Visa Information (Box 21)
  - Forestry (Box 21)
  - Form Letters (Box 21)
  - Form Letters to Members of the Graduate Council, 1941-1948 (Box 21)
  - Form Letters to Members of the Graduate Council, 1948-1949 (Box 21)
  - Form letters sent to Professors concerning "Incomplete" Graduates, 1948 Aug. 12-1951 Sept. 6 (Box 21)
  - Form Letters, 1948-1950 (Box 22)
  - Form Letters, 1950-1951 (Box 22)
  - Form Letters, Awards, 1955 (Box 22)
  - Forms, Memorandums (Box 22)
  - Fund for the Republic, The (Box 22)
  - Fulbright Scholarships, General, 1949-1952 (Box 22)
  - Fulbright Scholarships, Cancelled (Box 22)
  - Correspondence, General, 1955-1956 (Box 22)
  - Correspondence, General, 1962 Sept.-1963 Sept. (Box 22)
  - Correspondence, General, 1963 Sept.-1964 Sept. (Box 22)
  - Correspondence, General, 1964 Sept.-1965 Sept. (Box 22)
  - Correspondence, General, 1965 Sept.-1966 Sept. (Box 22)
  - Correspondence, General, 1966 Sept.-1967 Sept. (Box 22)
  - Education Board, General, 1939-1943 (Box 23)
  - Education Board, General, 1955 (Box 23)
  - Education Board, General, 1950-1952 (Box 23)
  - General Information (Box 23)
  - German (Box 23)
  - Germanic Languages and Literature, Department of, 1956-1958 (Box 23)
  - German, Graduate Work in, 1940 (Box 23)
  - German Auditors, 1950 (Box 23)
  - German Students, 1949-1950 (Box 23)
  - Graduate Appointments - Fellows, Scholars, Assistants, Stipend, Tenure, 1937-1938 (Box 23)
  - Graduate Clubs, 1944 (Box 23)
  - Graduate Clubs, Departmental (Box 23)
  - Graduate Courses Offered, 1950 (Box 23)
  - Graduate Dormitory, New, 1950 (Box 23)
  - Graduate Distribution Report, 1948-1949 (Box 23)
  - Graduates, Graduate, by Departments, 1938 (Box 23)
  - Graduating Practices (Box 23)
  - Graduate Education, Miscellaneous (Box 23)
  - Graduate Faculty, General, 1952-1953 (Box 24)
  - Graduate Faculty, Publicity, Etc., 1948 (Box 24)
  - Graduate Faculty, Meeting Minutes (Box 24)
  - Graduate Faculty, 1952 (Box 24)
  - Graduate Faculty, Agendas, 1956-1959 (Box 24)
  - Graduate Faculty, Committee Reports (Box 24)
  - Graduate Study for Teachers Brochure (Box 24)
  - Graduate Reception, 1950-1952 (Box 24)
  - Graduate Record Examination, 1944 (Box 24)
  - Graduate Record Examination, 1949, 1957 (Box 24)
  - Graduate Record Examination Office, 1950 (Box 25)
  - GRE Report (Box 25)
  - Graduate School, 1946 (Box 25)
  - Graduate School, Alumni (Box 25)
  - Graduate School, Bulletin, 1951-1952 (Box 25)
  - Graduate School Council, 1935 (Box 25)
  - Graduate School Council, Members, 1939-1944 (Box 25)
  - Graduate School Council, 1948-1949 (Box 25)
  - Graduate School Council, General, 1949-1953 (Box 25)
  - Graduate Council, Membership, 1950-1952 (Box 25)
  - Graduate Council, Petitions to (Box 25)
  - Graduate School, Open House, 1954-1955 (Box 25)
  - Graduate School, Policies and Regulations (Box 25)
  - Graduate School, Rating, Information of (Box 25)
  - Graduate School, Reception (Box 25)
  - Graduate School, Regulations, 1938 (Box 26)
  - Graduate Regulations at Other Universities (Box 26)
  - Graduate Student Council (Box 26)
  - Graduate and Undergraduate Schools in Relation to Professional Schools (Box 26)
  - Graduate Schools, Other, Correspondence with, 1950-1956 (Box 26)
  - Graduate Students by Department, 1963 Fall (Box 26)
  - Graduate Students, Notices and general letters sent to all, 1946 (Box 26)
  - Graduate Students, Notices, 1950-1956 (Box 26)
  - Gross, Paul M., 1949 (Box 26)
  - Gross, Paul M., 1950-1953 (Box 26)
  - Grant-In-Aid, College Teachers, 1952 (Box 26)
  - Grant-In-Aid, Offers refused,, 1953 Spring, Summer (Box 26)
  - Grant-In-Aid, 1953 Summer (Box 26)
  - Grant-In-Aid, Form Letters, Spring and Summer (Box 26)
  - Grant-In-Aid, Prospects, 1954 (Box 27)
  - Grant-In-Aid, A-K, 1954 (Box 27)
  - Grant-In-Aid, L-Z, 1954 (Box 27)
  - Grant-In-Aid, Luncheon, 1954-1955 (Box 27)
  - Grant-In-Aid, Offers Made, 1955 (Box 27)
  - Grant-In-Aid, Prospects, 1955 (Box 27)
  - Grant-In-Aid, Rejected, 1955 (Box 27)
  - Grants-In-Aid, Acceptances, 1956 Summer (Box 27)
  - Grants-In-Aid, Rejections, 1956 Summer (Box 27)
  - Grants-In-Aid, Possible Recipients for 1957 Grants-In-Aid, 1956 Summer (Box 27)
  - Grant-In-Aid, Scholarship Offers, 1957 Summer (Box 27)
  - Grant-In-Aid, Rejections, 1957 Summer (Box 28)
  - Grant-In-Aid, Recommended Candidates, 1957 Summer (Box 28)
  - Grant-In-Aid, 1958 Summer (Box 28)
  - Grant-In-Aid, Rejections, 1958 Summer (Box 28)
  - Grant-In-Aid, 1961 Summer (Box 28)
  - Grant-In-Aid, 1962 (Box 28)
  - Grant-In-Aid, 1963 (Box 28)
  - Grant-In-Aid, Survey (Box 28)
  - Gross, Paul M., 1955-1956 (Box 28)
  - Gross, Vice President P. M., 1956-1958 (Box 28)
  - Groves, Dr. Ernest R., 1941 (Box 28)
  - Guidance Program (Box 28)
  - Hall, Dr. F. G., 1948 (Box 28)
  - Harrar, Professor E. S., 1948 (Box 28)
  - Henricksen, C. C., 1955-1956 (Box 28)
  - Henricksen, C. C. (Box 28)
  - Herring, Dean H. J., 1955-1956 (Box 28)
  - Herring, Dean H. J. (Box 28)
  - Historical Society of North Carolina, 1948-1951 (Box 28)
  - History Department, 1945-1949 (Box 28)
  - History Department (Box 28)